Guide to the New-York Historical Society Pictorial Archive 1804-2009 (bulk 1900s-1970s) NYHS-RG 5
New-York Historical Society
- Series XI. Negatives, circa 1900-1990s; 11.38 Linear feet
  - Negative #36964-37523. Film, 5x7, 1952-1954 (Box 56, Envelope -)
    Exhibitions: Charles Lennox Wright: Pioneer of Zinc Etching (7); Old-Fashioned Winters (5); Early American Arts & Crafts (3); Spanish-American War Collection (6). Programs and Events: Strawberry Festival, 1953 (15); Children's story hour (8); Publicity appearance by Meryle Evans on Herb Sheldon's WWBT television show (5); St. Nicholas Festival (16). Staff Christmas Party (9). Memorial to George Zabriskie (7).
  - Negative #37623-37914. Film, 5x7, 1953-1954, Undated (Box 57, Envelope -)
    Programs and Events: Sesquicentennial (15); Arlene Francis television show broadcast from Prentis Collection rooms (3); Strawberry Festival (12). Images of various N-YHS historical documents, buildings, medals, etc., possibly for the sesquicentennial exhibition (24). Staff Christmas Party (16). Staff: Dorothy Barck (6).
  - Negative #37915-37936. Film, 5x7, 1954 (Box 58, Envelope -)
    Exhibitions: Tom Thumb (8); Slocum disaster (2); Hamilton-Burr duel (3). Programs and Events: Children's story hour (4); Publicity shot of Meryle Evans with Gouverneur Morris's wooden leg (1). Staff: Farewell party for Dorothy Barck (3).
  - Negative #37947. 35mm film strips in 8x10 envelopes, 1981 (Box 40, Envelope -)
    Exhibitions: Shakespeare in New York (3 strips, 17 images).
  - Negative #38037-38334. Film, 5x7, 1954-1955 (Box 58, Envelope -)
    Exhibitions: The Livingston Family Gift (4); 50th Anniversary of IRT Subway (3); 200th Anniversary of Fort Ticonderoga (4). Programs and Events: Sesquicentennial (21); St. Nicholas Festival (14); Presentation of model of S.S. Socony (2); Presentation of James Horan's manuscript of "Confederate Agent" (3). Staff Christmas Party (8).
  - Negative #38431-39022. Film, 5x7, 1954-1956 (Box 59, Envelope -)
    Exhibitions: Arnold Shircliffe Menu Collection (20); New York, The Empire State (5). Programs and Events: Strawberry Festival (9); Students in Port of New York Gallery (1); St. Nicholas Festival (10); Presentation of painting The Violinist, Carnegie Hall (6). Staff Christmas parties (12). Staff (9).
  - Negative #39110-39717. Film, 5x7, 1956-1957 (Box 60, Envelope -)
    Exhibitions: Presidential Campaign Cartoons (6); Christmas in New York (8); French in New York (2); New York, City of Authors signage (1); America in Daguerreotypes signage (1). Programs and Events: Strawberry Festival (18); Presentation of painting of General Burgoyne (6); Presentation of a 17th century Dutch Bible (6); St. Nicholas Festival (14); Visitors in 17th century costumes (2). Staff Christmas parties (9). Staff (2).
  - Negative #39719-40595. Film, 5x7, 1957-1958 (Box 61, Envelope -)
    Exhibitions: Prentis Gallery (2); Second Hardest Job in the World (5); 16th exhibition of painting (1); Stuyvesant Family portraits (3); Cartoons by C.D. Batchelor (2); It Paid to Advertise (Landauer) (14); America in Daguerreotypes (8). Programs and Events: Lafayette meeting (6); N-YHS Gold Medal to Thomas Streeter (7); Students sketching carriages (6); St. Nicholas Festival (8); Presentation of "Mary Powell" bell (3). Staff Christmas Party (8).
  - Negative #40628-40896. Film, 5x7, 1958-1959 (Box 62, Envelope -)
    Programs and Events: St. Nicholas Festivals (20); Unveiling of LeRoy Kimball portrait (8); Strawberry Festival (13); Installation of Beekman Room (1). Staff Christmas Parties (34). Staff (2).
  - Negative #40897-41334. Film, 5x7, 1959-1961 (Box 63, Envelope -)
    Exhibitions: Niagara Falls (10). Programs and Events: St. Nicholas Festival (15); N-YHS Gold Medal to R.W.G. Vail (12); Strawberry Festival (19). Staff events: Christmas Party (2); Farewell party for Vail (5). Staff (11).
  - Negative #41348-41855. Film, 5x7, 1960-1961 (Box 64, Envelope -)
    Programs and Events: St. Nicholas Festival (20); Strawberry Festival (19). Staff events: Farewell party for Garrett Winter (9), Edith Slattery & James Nebbergall (7); Christmas card (1); Christmas parties (22). Staff (3). N-YHS signage in subway (1).
  - Negative #41961-42019. Film, 5x7, 1961-1962 (Box 65, Envelope -)
    Exhibitions: New York City Hotels (9). Programs and Events: St. Nicholas Festival (12).
  - Negative #42609-42653. Film, 8x10, 1939, 1962 (Box 35, Envelope -)
    Exhibitions: Civil War Behind the Lines (6); War of 1812 (8); American Silhouette Portraits (7); Passenger Transportation on Manhattan (5); Rare Books (5). Building exterior (2)
  - Negative #42688-43292. Film, 8x10, 1955, 1963-1968, Undated (Box 36, Envelope -)
    Exhibitions: Theatres of the 1880s (3); American Silver (11); Audubon (11); American Military Weapons & Equipment (6); Ezra Ames (2); Merchants & Planters of the Upper Hudson (12); Circus Posters (6); Transportation in Old New York (7); Historic Hudson (6); America in Allegory (1); Theatrical Posters (5); Colorful New Yorkiana (1); Treasures of N-YHS (5); Unidentified (10). Galleries and Rooms (9). N-YHS exhibition at the New York City World's Fair (10).
  - Negative #43313-44577. Film, 5x7, 1962-1964, Undated (Box 65, Envelope -)
    Exhibitions: Prentis Rooms (13); Prentis Murphy Toy Collection (4); American Silver (1); Presidents and Statesmen (1); Audubon gallery (1); Images (color transparency negative) taken for N-YHS exhibition at World's Fair (12). Programs and Events: St. Nicholas Festival (2); Educational events for children (5). Buildings, interior (2); exterior (2). Staff events: Christmas party (2); Party for Sally Ryan (4). Images of N-YHS historical buildings, documents (5).
  - Negative #44747-45191. Film, 5x7, 1964-1965 (Box 66, Envelope -)
    Programs and Events: Story Hour (6); Students researching (1); School class in Volunteer Fire Department gallery (4). Staff event: Farewell party for Jack Kennan (6). Staff (1).
  - Negative #45304. Film, 8x10, 1970 (Box 36, Envelope -)
    Exhibitions: Eye on the City (1).
  - Negative #45361-48317. Film, 5x7, 1965, 1967-1968 (Box 66, Envelope -)
    Exhibitions: New York City Milestone (2); Gallery of Art, 1968 4th floor installation (22). Programs and Events: Story Hour (4); School class in New York Gallery (3). Signage (1), Unidentified (1).
  - Negative #48770-48771. Film, 8x10, 1970 (Box 36, Envelope -)
    Galleries and Rooms: Books in Librarian's Office (2).
  - Negative #48891-49831. Film, 5x7, 1968-1969 (Box 66, Envelope -)
    Exhibitions: Gallery of Art, 1968 4th floor installation (7); Central Park: Oasis in Manhattan (4). Buildings: York & Sawyer rendering (1); South Gallery before 1969 reinstallation (7); Richard Hunt Morris plans for an N-YHS building in Central Park (2).
  - Negative #50000-50260. Film, 5x7, 1968-1970 (Box 67, Envelope -)
    Exhibitions: A Decade of Collecting (16); George Catlin: Artist of the American Indian (3); New York: Maritime City (2). Staff (1).
  - Negative #50383-50384. Film, 8x10, 1970 (Box 36, Envelope -)
    Signage: N-YHS Directory (2).
  - Negative #50505-50525. Film, 5x7, 1970? (Box 67, Envelope -)
    Exhibitions: Eye on the City(?) (20).
  - Negative #50601-50660. Film, 8x10, 1970-1971 (Box 36, Envelope -)
    Exhibitions: Eye on the City (6); City of Promise: Aspects of Jewish Life in New York (17).
  - Negative #50760-50977. Film, 5x7, 1971 (Box 67, Envelope -)
    Exhibitions: City of Promise: Aspects of Jewish Life in New York (18); Classics of 17th Century Americana (4); Society's Sculpture (2).
  - Negative #51470-51698. Film, 8x10, 1971-1973 (Box 37, Envelope -)
    Exhibitions: McCullough Hall Park Collection (1); John Rogers' Household Gods (10); Paperweights (10); Audubon (26); Road to the White House (5); Society's Sculpture ( 28). Signage: Directory (1)
  - Negative #51902-51949. Film, 5x7, 1972 (Box 67, Envelope -)
    Exhibitions: Miniatures & Medals (4). Certificate of Accreditation from the American Association of Museums (1). Images of historical documents concerning 1860s Audubon acquisition (3).
  - Negative #51950-52418. Film, 5x7, 1972 (Box 68, Envelope -)
    Exhibitions: Toy installation (29). Staff events: Farewell party for Ingrid Maerta Held (3), Joseph Rapport (6). Objects: Gold Medal presented to George C.D. Odell in 1942.
  - Negative #52455-52876. Film, 8x10, 1973-1974 (Box 37, Envelope -)
    Exhibitions: New York to 1765 (49); Be My Valentine (10); Old New York in Early Photographs (9).
  - Negative #52894-53144. Film, 8x10, 1974-1975 (Box 38, Envelope -)
    Exhibitions: Manhattan Now (28); Deck the Halls (8).
  - Negative #53256. Film, 5x7, 1974 (Box 68, Envelope -)
    Buildings: N-YHS entrance (1).
  - Negative #53404-53574. Film, 8x10, 1940, 1975, Undated (Box 38, Envelope -)
    Exhibitions: John Pintard & His Society (8); Ain't I a Woman? (1); Jacques Reich (1); Shaker Photographs & Small Crafts (16); Unidentified (28); Galleries and Rooms (4). Building exterior (1). Programs and Events (1).
  - Negative #53618-53741. Film, 5x7, 1973-1976 (Box 68, Envelope -)
    Exhibitions: Joseph Raskin: Master Etcher (9). Objects: Fence from Bowling Green (object x.475) (1); Commemorative medal from the Netherlands (object 1977.1) (1). Buildings: Central Park West exterior pre-1937 (1), floor plans (2). Staff events: Retirement parties for Eddie Santrucek & Bill Baillie (4) and A. Calderelli (4).
  - Negative #54370-54683. Film, 8x10, 1975-1976 (Box 38, Envelope -)
    Exhibitions: American Folk Art (1); Sword of Rebellion is Drawn (39); The Cabinetmaker and His Use of Space (16); Words & Music: Sheet Music of Not So Long Ago (4).
  - Negative #54694-54972. Film, 8x10, 1976, Undated (Box 39, Envelope -)
    Exhibitions: History at Home (12); Sword of Rebellion is Drawn (1); Unidentified (11).
  - Negative #55048. Film, 5x7, 1961 (Box 68, Envelope -)
    Objects: Loan of astrolabe (object 1943.192) to Canada (4).
  - Negative #55168-55242. Film, 8x10, 1977 (Box 39, Envelope -)
    Exhibitions: William Bradford imprints (1); Moving in the City (11); Think Small/Miniatures (1). Galleries and Rooms (2).
  - Negative #55472-55495. Film, 5x7, 1977 (Box 68, Envelope -)
    Buildings, interior (1). Unidentified event (2).
  - Negative #56037-56883. Film, 8x10, 1978-1979 (Box 39, Envelope -)
    Exhibitions: New Life for Old Objects (15); Resorts in 19th Century New York State (10); Street Kids (32); Audubon & His World (6); World War I Posters (17); New York Eats Out: Menus (10); 25 Years of Acquisitions (5); Revisiting the World's Fair of 1939 (8).
  - Negative #56889-57033. Film, 5x7, 1984, Undated (Box 68, Envelope -)
    Exhibitions: Catalogue cover for New York and the China Trade (1). Programs and Events: Strawberry Festival, 1939 (3).
  - Negative #57150. 35mm film strips in 8x10 envelopes, 1984 (Box 40, Envelope -)
    Exhibition: Temperance Movements in America (4 strips; 23 images).
  - Negative #57701-57705. Film, 5x7, 1981 (Box 68, Envelope -)
    Exhibitions: Valentine...Be Mine (5).
  - Negative #57735-58056. 35mm film strips in 8x10 envelopes, 1981-1982 (Box 40, Envelope -)
    Exhibitions: Cutting Edge: Silhouetts by Auguste Edouart (5 strips, 28 images); Tales of Christmas Past (5 strips, 29 images); George Washington in New York State (6 strips, 31 images).
  - Negative #58118. Film, 5x7, 1985 (Box 68, Envelope -)
    Buildings: Central Park West, interior (1).
  - Negative #58551. 35mm film strips in 8x10 envelopes, 1982 (Box 40, Envelope -)
    Exhibitions: Colonial Americana from the Collections of N-YHS (6 strips, 36 images).
  - Negative #58806-58826. Film, 5x7, 1982, Undated (Box 69, Envelope -)
    Buildings: Central Park West, interior (1); 1930s exteriors and floor plan (4).
  - Negative #58963. 35mm film strips in 8x10 envelopes, 1984 (Box 40, Envelope -)
    Exhibitions: Struggle for a Continent: Francis Parkman's France and England in North America (7 strips, 42 images).
  - Negative #59041-59254. Film, 5x7, 1982-1983 (Box 69, Envelope -)
    Buildings: Central Park West, interior (13), exterior (2 35mm strips, 6 images).
  - Negative #59265-59287. 35mm film strips in 8x10 envelopes, 1982-1984 (Box 40, Envelope -)
    Exhibitions: Accessions: 1980-82 (6 strips, 35 images); Library of John Pintard: Book Collecting in the New Republic (4 strips, 24 images); Sons of St. Patrick: The Irish and Irish Organizations in New York City (6 strips, 31 images); Greetings of the Year (6 strips, 35 images); American Landscape Painting, Genre Art and Drawing (4 strips, 16 images); Celebration of Opera in Honor of the Metropolitan Opera's 100th Birthday (6 strips, 31 images).
  - Negative #59348-59389. Film, 5x7, 1982-1983 (Box 69, Envelope -)
    Exhibitions: Audubon Birds of America gallery (3). Buildings: Central Park West interior (4), exterior circa 1915 (1).
  - Negative #59609. 35mm film strips in 8x10 envelopes, [1983] (Box 40, Envelope -)
    Exhibition: Brooklyn Bridge (14 strips, 81 images).
  - Negative #60636-61661. Film, 5x7, 1982-1984, Undated (Box 69, Envelope -)
    Exhibitions: World of Tiffany: Neustadt Collection (14). Buildings: Central Park West 1983 plan (1); interiors (3); montage of 19th century N-YHS buildings. Image of 1866 Brady letter to N-YHS (2).
  - Negative #61836-61842. 35mm film strips in 8x10 envelopes, 1982-1984 (Box 40, Envelope -)
    Exhibitions: Treasures of Manuscript Americana (4 strips, 20 images); The Black Experience in New York (6 strips, 36 images); Cultural Pleasures of 18th & 19th Century New York: Centennial Tribute to the Grolier Club (6 strips, 32 images); The Female Touch: Ladies' Periodical as a Reflection of an Age (6 strips, 36 images).
  - Negative #63419-64109. Film, 5x7, 1986 (Box 69, Envelope -)
    Buildings: Central Park West, exterior (4), interior of museum store (4); 2nd Avenue plan by Carstensen & Gildemeister (1).
  - Negative #64210-64211. Film, 8x10, 1982 (Box 39, Envelope -)
    Exhibition: Oom Pah Pah: Great American Band (12).
  - Negative #64259-72894. Film, 5x7, 1965, 1986, 1990s? (Box 69, Envelope -)
    Exhibitions: Prized Prints (5). Objects: 1810 St. Nicholas Festival description from Pintard papers (1). Buildings: Central Park West, 1906 interior (1); Bus stop (2); Cass Gilbert collection in stacks (3). Programs and Events: Children in auditorium (1).
  - 1937-1938 Building Expansion Negatives (Box 40, Envelope -)
    In 2016, over 200 acetate negatives related to the 1937-38 building expansion were removed from the collection because of their severely deteriorated condition. Only 24 negatives were in sufficiently good condition to retain. This folder holds those 24, the report on the disposition of the other negatives, and the list of negatives scanned prior to disposition. See also above at NYHS-RG 5, Series I, folder 170 Central Park West. Construction. New Wings (6 of 6).